(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T22:36:14.868130",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はるか昔
Long ago...
西の海に沈んだとされる 伝説の都市
...a legendary city said to have sunk in the western sea,
アトロボリス
Atroboris.
そんな 誰もいないはずの海の底に
At the bottom of that sea, where no one should be,
ロボットの少女がひとり
there is a single robot girl.
彼女の歌声は
Her singing voice...
都市を再び浮上させる唯一の鍵
...is the only key to bringing the city back to the surface.
「今宵… この街を再び地上へ…」
"Tonight... I will bring this city back to the surface..."
これは 一夜限りの夢の祭典
This is a dream festival for one night only.
泡となって…
Turning into bubbles...
消える都市の
The vanishing city's...
最後の物語
...final story.
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah...
だめ だめ だめ 脳みその中から
No, no, no, from inside my brain...
「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
...morality hollers, "Stop it, you idiot!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン
Darling, baby darling,
ハンパなくラブ！と煌めき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
philosophy gets flustered and sparkles with "Unreal love!"
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
A glance from below, cute enough to die for,
何がし法に触れるくらい
enough to break some kind of law.
ばら撒く乱心 気付けば当人
Scattering madness, before I know it, I'm the one—
この世に生まれた君が悪い
it's your fault for being born into this world.
やたらとシンドイ恋煩い
This excruciating lovesickness,
バラバラなる頭とこの身体
my head and body falling all to pieces.
頸動脈から「愛してる」が噴き出して
Out from my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out...
アイリスアウト
Iris out.
一体どうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What to do with these feelings?
肋のザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The granulated sugar in my ribs melts, feels like I'll throw up.
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にそう
My pupils wide open, feels like I'll drown and die.
今 この世で君だけ大正解
Right now in this world, only you are the absolute right answer.
ダーリン（ベイビー） ダーリン
Darling (baby), darling.
ひっくり返しても勝ち目ない
Even if flipped, there's no chance of winning.
君だけルールは適用外
Only for you, the rules don't apply.
四つ端もオセロは黒しかないカツアゲ放題
All four corners, Othello has only black—unlimited shakedown.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
The Avada Kedavra you cast with a smile,
デコにスティグマ申し訳ねえな
a stigma on my forehead, sorry about that.
矢を指して
Point the arrow,
貫いて
pierce it through,
ここ弱点
here is my weak spot.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
A glance from below, cute enough to die for,
何がし法に触れるくらい
enough to break some kind of law.
ばら撒く乱心 気付けば当人
Scattering madness, before I know it, I'm the one—
この世に生まれた君が悪い
it's your fault for being born into this world.
パチモンでもいい何でもいい
Even a knockoff is fine, anything is fine,
今 君と名付いてる全て欲しい
right now, I want everything that carries your name.
頸動脈から「愛してる」が噴き出して
Out from my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out...
アイリスアウト
Iris out.
一体どうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What to do with these feelings?
肋のザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The granulated sugar in my ribs melts, feels like I'll throw up.
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にそう
My pupils wide open, feels like I'll drown and die.
今 この世で君だけ大正解
Right now in this world, only you are the absolute right answer.
ダーリン（ベイビー） ダーリン
Darling (baby), darling.
Ah...
嫌い 好き 嫌い 好き
Dislike, like, dislike, like,
嫌い 嫌い
dislike, dislike,
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
dislike, dislike, dislike, dislike.
自己満中途半端はやめて
Stop the self-satisfying half measures,
一番ダサいことの体現者
the embodiment of the lamest thing.
一生飼い犬にでも成るつもり
Do you intend to just be a kept dog for life?
満身創痍で血を隠す
Covering the blood while riddled with wounds.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet!
もういいかい ダイスキを貫け
Are you ready? Pierce through with love!
未公開
Undisclosed.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
もう もういいよね
It's already enough, right?
強制 let's go!
Mandatory, let's go!
好き 嫌い 大嫌い 好き
Like, dislike, hate, like!
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 大好き
Dislike, dislike, dislike, love!
ボクはボクが嫌い 愛せない
I dislike myself, can't love myself.
声も顔も嫌い 大嫌い
I dislike my voice and face, hate them.
今日も作り笑い 愛せない
Faking a smile again today, can't love it.
過去は死んだ未来 大嫌い
The past is a dead future, hate it.
誰のせいだ
Whose fault is it?
ボクのせいじゃない
It's not my fault.
自慰行為 何も生まない同士
Self-gratification, mutual companions producing nothing,
消耗乳繰り合う猿芝居
a farcical play of draining flirtations.
自暴自棄位が丁度いい
Self-abandonment is just about right,
己を投げ捨てて自己覚醒
throwing myself away and achieving self-awakening.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet!
もういいかい ダイスキを貫け
Are you ready? Pierce through with love!
非公開
Private.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
もう もういいよね
It's already enough, right?
蘇生 let's go!
Resurrection, let's go!
好き 嫌い 大嫌い 好き
Like, dislike, hate, like!
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 大好き
Dislike, dislike, dislike, love!
ボクはキミが嫌い 愛せない
I dislike you, can't love you.
パパもママも嫌い 大嫌い
I dislike Papa and Mama too, hate them.
皆被害者みたい 愛せない
Everyone acts like a victim, can't love them.
ボク等生きる機械 大嫌い
We are living machines, hate it.
誰のせいだ
Whose fault is it?
ボクは悪くない
I did nothing wrong.
好き 嫌い 大嫌い 好き
Like, dislike, hate, like!
嫌い
Dislike...
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
I hate it, I hate it, I hate it.
手鏡なんて見てないで
Don't look in the hand mirror,
起死回生 先を睨め
resurrect and glare ahead.
再生 未体験ゾーン
Reborn into an unexperienced zone.
そうさだって 自信は後からついてくる
That's right, because confidence will follow.
一歩踏み出したならば cool
If you take a step forward, that's cool.
苦痛も鬱も続く on my mind
Pain and depression keep going on in my mind.
再度確認 最初の動機をもう一度思い出そう
Double check, remember your initial motive once more.
悔しい今日 ひっくり返そう
Let's overturn this frustrating today.
悔しいほど 強くなられ
Become stronger through your frustration.
右左見たり 下を見て安心してるうちは ah
As long as you look left, right, and down to feel safe, ah,
誰にもなれない 君になれんのは君だけ
you can't be anyone; only you can be yourself.
近道生み出せ リアリティ
Forge a shortcut into reality,
全宇宙 全世界 無二になれ let's go!
across the whole universe and world, become one and only, let's go!
さらけ出して 君次第で全部変わる
Lay it all bare; everything changes depending on you.
ベール剥がす ドロドロした中身暴く
Tear off the veil, expose the muddy core inside.
いつの間にか見失った 宝物はどこに行った
Where did the lost treasure go before we realized?
ドキドキした オープニング
That thrilling beginning.
思い出して初期衝動 青い春を事の最初
Remember the initial impulse, youth at the very start.
それが本当 芯の誠
That's the real truth at the core.
誰も同じ 堕落 摩擦
Everyone's the same: downfall and friction.
かわるがわる回る苦楽
Joy and sorrow rotating one after another.
君の人生 誰の人生
Your life, whose life is it?
一度きりの博打しようよ
Let's make this once-in-a-lifetime gamble.
あなたはすぐに
You are always so quick
写真を撮りたがる
to want to take photos.
あたしはいつも
I always
其れを嫌がるの
hate it when you do.
だって写真になっちゃえば
Because if it becomes a photo,
あたしが古くなるじゃない
I'll become something of the past, won't I?
あなたはすぐに
You are always so quick
絶対などと云う
to say things like "forever."
あたしはいつも
I always
其れを嫌がるの
hate it when you do.
だって冷めてしまっちゃえば
Because if things grow cold,
其れすら嘘になるじゃない
even those words will turn into lies, won't they?
Don't you think? I wanna be with you
此処に居て ずっと ずっと ずっと
Stay right here, forever and ever and ever.
明日のことは判らない
We don't know what tomorrow brings,
だからぎゅっとしていてね
so please hold me tight,
ぎゅっとしていてね
hold me tight,
ダーリン
darling.
あなたはすぐに
You are always so quick
いじけて見せたがる
to sulk and pout.
あたしはいつも
I always
其れを喜ぶの
take delight in it.
だってカートみたいだから
Because since you look like Kurt,
あたしがコートニーじゃない
doesn't that make me Courtney?
Don't you think? I wanna be with you
傍に来て もっと もっと もっと
Come close to me, closer, closer, closer.
昨日のことは忘れちゃおう
Let's just forget about yesterday,
そしてぎゅっとしていてね
and please hold me tight,
ぎゅっとしていてね
hold me tight,
ダーリン
darling.
また四月が来たよ
April has come around again,
同じ日のことを思い出して
remembering that very same day.
Don't you think? I wanna be with you
此処に居て
Stay right here...
ずっと ずっと ずっと...
Always, always, always...
明日のことは 分からない
I don't know what tomorrow will bring,
だから ぎゅっとしててね
so please hold me tight.
Ah, I wanna be with you
傍に来て もっと もっと もっと
Come close to me, more, more, and more...
昨日のことは 忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about yesterday,
そして ぎゅっとしててね
and hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしててね
Hold me tight,
ダーリン
darling.
はーい！というわけで...
Alright! And with that...
ハローボ！
Hello-bo!
ホロライブ0期生
Hololive Generation 0,
バーチャル高性能ロボットのロボ子だよー！
virtual high-spec robot, Roboco here!
今日はボクの誕生日ライブに来てくれて ありがとうー！
Thank you all so much for coming to my birthday live show today!
というわけで 早速『Eyes Out』『DANCE with TRANCE-ROID』
So, right off the bat, "Eyes Out", "DANCE with TRANCE-ROID",
そして『ギブス』の3曲をね 歌わせていただきましたー！
and "Gips" were the three songs I performed!
いかがでしたでしょうかー？
How did you like them?
そして いかがでしょうか このステージ！
And how do you like this stage?!
まだね この衣装のモチーフではないんですけれども
It's not themed after this outfit yet, but...
新衣装のね プラスドール衣装にちなんで作ってみましたー！
...we made it based on my new doll outfit!
このステージは もうさっきの3曲でも もう分かるんだけど
As you might have noticed from the first three songs,
これからどんどん化けるので 楽しみにしていてください！
this stage will keep transforming, so please look forward to it!
色んなね 姿で楽しめる
You'll get to enjoy all kinds of different looks!
今はめっちゃ 骨骨骨骨骨骨！
Right now it's all bones, bones, bones, bones, bones!
魚も骨！
Even the fish are bones!
え めちゃめちゃ可愛くない？
Hehe, isn't it super cute?
大好きなんだよなぁ
I really love it.
そう こちらはですね 海底が 海底都市がね テーマになっています
Yes, the theme here is the ocean floor—an undersea city.
え こちらの都市の名前は 冒頭のオープニングでも言っていたんですけど
The name of this city, as I mentioned during the opening earlier,
「アット・ロポリス」 アット・ロポリスって言います！
is "At-Ropolis"—it's called At-Ropolis!
ロポじゃない ロボ！ロボ ロボで ロボ！
Not "Ropo", Robo! Robo, as in Robot! Haha!
本来は海の底にあるね 都市なんですけれども
It's originally a city located at the bottom of the sea,
1日だけ ロボ子の歌のパワーで浮上させてるんだよー！
but for today only, I raised it with the power of Roboco's singing!
どうだ すごいだろー！
How about that? Pretty amazing, right?
そう ここは息吸えるの！ えへへへへ
Yeah, you can breathe here! Ehehehe.
うん！
Yup!
ぜひね いっぱい たくさん スクリーンショット
Please take lots and lots of screenshots!
もう撮ってると思うけど いっぱい撮って
I'm sure you already have, but take a bunch,
こちらのハッシュタグもね 「#ロボ子海底3Dライブ」で どしどしポストしてってくれると嬉しいです！
and please post them using the hashtag "#RobokoKaitei3DLive"!
トレンドに入りたい！ よろしくお願いします！
I want to get on the trending list! Please help me make it happen!
誕生日は終わってしまったけど 誕生日のライブの
My actual birthday is already over, but I'm doing this
つもりでやっていますので はい！
with the spirit of a birthday live, yes!
年に一度のね いつもやらせていただいてますので ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Since I get to do this annual show, I hope you enjoy it!
今回のタグは「#ロボ子海底3Dライブ」でございます よろしくねー！
The tag this time is "#RobokoKaitei3DLive". Thank you all!
はーい！
Alright!
というわけでね どうでしたか ちなみに？
So anyway, how was it, by the way?
かっこよかった？
Did I look cool?
去年は竜とかに乗ってみたんだけど
Last year I tried riding a dragon,
今回はアトロポリスなんで サメとかにも乗ってみました！
but since we're in Atropolis this time, I rode a shark and stuff!
はい 今年もメロ女を目指してみたくて
Yeah, I wanted to aim for being an enchanting woman again,
あの メロ女になっていました？
so... did I seem like an enchanting woman?
メロ女... ボクはメロ女目指したいと思います！
An enchanting woman... I'll keep aiming to be one!
はい！
Yes!
まだね あ そう！ 気づいた？ フリフリしてきたやつ
Also... oh, right! Did you notice the fluttering things that fell down?
実は 今回は時間に余裕があったので
Actually, since we had plenty of time this time around,
事前にロボサーたちにね 募集をさせていただきまして
we held an open call for submissions from the Robosaa beforehand,
イラストが上から降ってくるようなギミックをね 用意いたしました！
and prepared a gimmick where illustrations flutter down from above!
採用された方はね
For those whose art was featured,
「え もしかして自分の絵があるのかもしれない」っていうドキドキを味わいながら探してみてください！
try looking for it while feeling the thrill of thinking, "Wait, is that my art?!"
まだまだ出てきますのでねー
More will keep coming up,
チャンスはまだあります！
so you still have plenty of chances!
誰が… 誰が描いたのが選ばれているのか、
Please look forward to seeing whose art was chosen!
ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Make sure to stick around!
めちゃめちゃもう可愛いのがいっぱい出てきてますのでね。
Lots of super cute ones have already shown up.
ゆっくり見てってください！
Please sit back and enjoy!
はい！それでは、まだまだありますので、
Alright! We still have so much more in store,
ここからはなんと、ゲストも登場するので！
and starting now, guests will actually appear!
一体何を歌うんだ？！
What on earth are they going to sing?!
楽しみにしててください！
Please look forward to it!
それじゃあ、まだまだ行くぞー！
Alright then, let's keep going!
見てってポストしてってー！
Watch and keep posting!
パシャ！
Snap!
嗚呼 一発じゃ足りないのかい
Ah, isn't one shot enough?
二発目をおかわりしたい
Want a second helping for round two?
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no "third time's the charm"
四の五の言うなよ
Don't complain about this and that
ろくでもない
It's all good for nothing!
茹だるような暑さが鬱陶しい
This sweltering heat is so annoying
夜は薄着の天使が騒々しい
At night, lightly dressed angels make a racket
露出ばかり増えるんじゃ意味ないね
Just showing more skin is meaningless
本当の意味での祭りはこれからさ
The real festival starts right now
火傷するくらいの近距離で
Close enough to get burned,
仕込むスターマイン
we set up the starmine
類を見ないような手順で
With an unprecedented procedure,
スタンバイ さぁ打ち上げろ
standby, come on, launch it!
嗚呼 一発じゃ足りないのかい
Ah, isn't one shot enough?
二発目をおかわりしたい
Want a second helping for round two?
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no "third time's the charm"
四の五の言うなよ
Don't complain about this and that
鍵屋 玉屋
Kagiya! Tamaya!
上がって がって 合点
Going up and up, got it!
でもね たまにゃ
But you know, once in a while,
下がって がって ガッデム
going down and down, goddamn!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no "third time's the charm"
四の五の言うなよ
Don't complain about this and that
ろくでもない
It's all good for nothing!
寄ってらっしゃい 見てらっしゃい
Come one, come all! Take a look!
でも外野はさっさと黙らっしゃい
But the outfield should just shut up!
わっしょい わっしょい
Wasshoi, wasshoi!
騒ぎ立てるより この瞬間大事にしな？
Rather than making a fuss, shouldn't you cherish this moment?
未曾有の炎色反応で
With an unprecedented flame reaction,
彩るのは過去じゃなく未来だけ
what we color isn't the past, only the future
息を呑むくらいのスピードで
At a speed that takes your breath away,
鳴らすスターマイン
we set off the starmine
釘付けになるド派手さで
With an eye-catching flashiness,
スタンバイ さぁ打ち上げろ
standby, come on, launch it!
嗚呼 一発じゃ足りないのかい
Ah, isn't one shot enough?
二発目をおかわりしたい
Want a second helping for round two?
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no "third time's the charm"
四の五の言うなよ
Don't complain about this and that
鍵屋 玉屋
Kagiya! Tamaya!
上がって がって 合点
Going up and up, got it!
でもね たまにゃ
But you know, once in a while,
下がって がって ガッデム
going down and down, goddamn!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no "third time's the charm"
四の五の言うなよ
Don't complain about this and that
ろくでもない
It's all good for nothing!
真っ暗な空を照らす
Illuminating the pitch-black sky,
命の火花散らそう
let's scatter the sparks of life
悲しみも吹き飛ばせ
Blow away all the sorrow
最大火力で
with maximum firepower!
さぁ打ち上げろ
Come on, launch it!
上がって がって 合点
Going up and up, got it!
でもね たまにゃ
But you know, once in a while,
下がって がって ガッデム
going down and down, goddamn!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no "third time's the charm"
四の五の言うなよ
Don't complain about this and that
もういいかい
Are you ready yet?
上がって がって 合点
Going up and up, got it!
でもね たまにゃ
But you know, once in a while,
下がって がって ガッデム
going down and down, goddamn!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no "third time's the charm"
四の五の言うなよ
Don't complain about this and that
ろくでもない
It's all good for nothing!
人生は七転び八起き九展開
Life is seven falls, eight rises, and nine plot twists!
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending a slightly urban night with you
処理速度高速 私から
High processing speed, from me
送るデータは膨大
the data I send is massive
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！
Saying "No way, I can't accept that!" is no good!
愛して twinkle night
Love me, twinkle night
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending a slightly urban night with you
甘々なひととき 君にオーダー
Ordering a sweet moment with you
手を取り
Taking my hand,
言葉と指を交わそうよ
let's exchange words and intertwine our fingers,
恋のセオリー
the theory of love.
今の暮らしは悪くなる一方です
My current life just keeps getting worse,
君と二人暮らす部屋が理想です
and a room living together with you is the ideal.
うだつが上がらない僕のそばで
Beside me, who can't seem to make any headway,
ずっと笑ってくれる君が好きです
I love how you're always smiling.
最高だよ人生 長い髪切って
Life is the best; cutting your long hair
君の好きな誰かに合わせて
to match someone you like,
音楽をかけるよ 僕がDJのRadio
I'll play music on the radio where I'm the DJ.
ポルノグラフィティみたいな感じ！どう？
Kind of like Porno Graffitti! How about that?
目と目が合う レーザービーム
Our eyes meet like laser beams,
漫画的偶然 手が触れた日
that manga-like coincidence the day our hands touched.
放電する二人 電気ガバチバチ
The two of us discharging, electricity crackling,
特性 蓄電 避雷針
special traits: storage battery, lightning rod.
唐突に喋り出すSiri
Siri abruptly starts talking,
君の言葉の裏 本当の意味
the true meaning behind your words.
これっきり ギリギリで
Holding on just barely at the very limit,
保ってるボクのハート
my heart
プラ製 でも溶けそう
is made of plastic, but it feels like it's about to melt.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, slightly urban,
処理速度 高速 私から
high processing speed, sent from me,
送るデータは膨大
the data is massive.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！愛して twinkle night
"I can't take it all" is not an option! Love me, twinkle night.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, slightly urban,
甘々なひととき 君にオーダー
ordering a super-sweet moment with you.
コマ送りメモリー イルミの前手を取り
Frame-by-frame memory; taking your hand before the illuminations,
言葉と指を交わそうよ 恋のセオリー
let's exchange words and intertwine our fingers, the theory of love.
ティンクルくるせいだーす
Twinkle Crusaders,
マーズ・アタック！ ザスラですら
even Mars Attacks! or Zathura...
全部架空 ヒエログリフだって
it's all fiction; even hieroglyphs
誰かの解釈 読めるわけないのにね
are just someone's interpretation—not like anyone can read them.
この物語はフィクションです
This story is a work of fiction;
君との遭遇は嘘なんです
my encounter with you was a lie.
feel alright 痛くも痒くもない
Feel alright, it doesn't hurt or itch at all,
けど 黄色ゲージ スタミナない
but my gauge is yellow—I've got no stamina.
教えてFilmarks 空っぽの人生
Tell me, Filmarks: for an empty life,
星何点？ 欲しがってる
how many stars? I'm longing for
満点の星 120個
a full score of 120 stars,
いや1個で十分かも
or maybe just one is enough.
Wow! Signal 送り返す
Sending back a "Wow! Signal",
君は返事もくれないまま
yet you still leave me without a reply.
炭酸のないサイダー
A flat cider soda,
飲み干せないや まだまだ
I still can't finish drinking it, not yet.
裸足のまま踊る夜
Dancing barefoot into the night,
寒くはないけどココアを飲む
I'm not cold, but I drink hot cocoa.
誰かが見てる 私も誰かを見てる
Someone is watching, and I'm watching someone too.
108 アメと恋とゲーム
108, candy, love, and games.
最高のfriendだ お布団
My best friend is my futon...
twinkle night たゆたう
Twinkle night, drifting away,
夢遊病患者の寝言
sleep-talk of a sleepwalker.
甘い雲はバニラの香りがするんだ
Sweet clouds smell of vanilla.
包んだはずの足は寒くて引っ込めた
I tucked my feet in, but they got cold so I pulled them back.
きっとまた はみ出した
I must have fallen asleep
ままで寝てしまったんだ
with them sticking out again.
まった あったまったらまた
Wait; once I warm up again,
彼方 あなたとなら 九日十日
far away, if it's with you, for nine or ten days.
どうか 音は星を超えた
Somehow, the sound reached beyond the stars.
そっか やっぱり夢か
I see... so it was just a dream after all.
わかっても 瞳は閉じたまま
Even knowing that, I keep my eyes closed.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, slightly urban,
処理速度 高速 私から
high processing speed, sent from me,
送るデータは膨大
the data is massive.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！愛して twinkle night
"I can't take it all" is not an option! Love me, twinkle night.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, slightly urban,
甘々なひととき 君にオーダー
ordering a super-sweet moment with you.
コマ送りメモリー イルミの前手を取り
Frame-by-frame memory; taking your hand before the illuminations,
言葉と指を交わそうよ 恋のセオリー
let's exchange words and intertwine our fingers, the theory of love.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, slightly urban,
処理速度 高速 私から
high processing speed, sent from me,
送るデータは膨大
the data is massive.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！愛して twinkle night
"I can't take it all" is not an option! Love me, twinkle night.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the whole wide world—
そういう扱い 心得てよね
you'd better know how to treat me like one, okay?
やーね！
Jeez!
ワールドイズマイン CPK! Remix
[Song: World is Mine (CPK! Remix)]
1, 2, 3!
その一 いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Number one: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual.
その二 ちゃんと靴までみること いいね？
Number two: Make sure to check out my shoes too, got it?
その三 わたしの一言には３つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Reply to every word I say with three words.
わかったら右手がお留守なのを なんとかして！
If you understand, do something about my lonely right hand!
べつに わがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
きみに 心から思ってほしいの かわいいって
I just want you to think I'm cute from the bottom of your heart.
かわいいって
That I'm cute!
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the whole wide world—
気がついて ねえねえ
pay attention to me, hey, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question.
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？ もうなんだか
Who do you think I am? Geez, I kind of...
甘いものが食べたい
I want to eat something sweet!
今すぐに
Right this instant!
Yeah
Hey baby
欠点？ かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You must mean my cute quirks, right?
文句は許しませんの
I won't accept any complaints!
あのね？ 私の話 ちゃんと聞いてる？ ちょっと…
Hey, are you listening to what I'm saying? Excuse me...
あ、それとね？ 白いお馬さん 決まってるでしょ？
Oh, and by the way, a white horse is a given, right?
迎えに来て
Come pick me up.
分かったら 傅いて 手を取って「お姫様」って
If you understand, kneel down, take my hand, and call me "Princess."
べつに わがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
でもね 少しぐらい 叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit, right?
世界で わたしだけの王子様
My one and only prince in the whole world,
気がついて ほらほら おててがあいてます
notice me, look, look! My hand is open and waiting!
無口で 無愛想な王子様
You silent, blunt prince...
もう どうして 気がついてよ 早く
Geez, why? Notice me already, hurry!
絶対 キミは 分かってない！ 分かってないわ
You definitely don't get it! You really don't get it!
わー
Wahhh~
Yeah
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Shortcake topped with strawberries,
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
melting pudding made with specially selected eggs...
みなみな 我慢します
I'll hold myself back from all of them,
わがままな子だと思わないで
so please don't think I'm a selfish girl.
わたしだってやればできるもん
Even I can do it if I try!
あとで後悔するわよ
You're going to regret this later!
当然です！ だってわたしは
Of course! Because after all, I am...
世界で 一番おひめさま
the number one princess in the world!
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Keep your eyes on me, okay? Or I might wander off somewhere!
ふいに抱きしめられた 急に そんな え？
Suddenly pulled into a hug... so out of nowhere, huh?
「轢かれる 危ないよ」
"You'll get hit, watch out!"
そう言って そっぽ向く キミ
Saying that, you look the other way...
こっちのが危ないわよ
You're the one who's dangerous!
Yeah
Hey baby
はーい！ というわけで
All right! And with that,
3曲連続でお届けしましたが、どうでしたかー？
I just performed three songs in a row! How did you like them?
『Starry Night』に、ポルカ、ベーちゃん、ビブ、そしてちはー！
In "Starry Night", with Polka, Bae-chan, Biboo, and Chiha-!
5人で歌いましたー！
The five of us sang together!
めっちゃめちゃかっこよくなかったー？
Didn't it look super, super cool?
なんかいいよね、みんなで一緒に踊るのっていいよね！
It's so nice, isn't it? Dancing together with everyone is great!
そして、『Twinkle Night』を、ぺこらと一緒に歌いましたー！
And then, I sang "Twinkle Night" together with Pekora!
そして、最後は『ワールドイズマイン』、CPKのRemixバージョンになりまーす！
And lastly, "World Is Mine", in the CPK remix version!
世界で一番お姫様だったー？
Was I the number one princess in the world?
お姫様だったー？
Was I your princess?
ここでもね、みんなに募集したイラストが降ってきましたけど、
Here as well, the illustrations you all submitted came raining down,
自分のみつけられた人いたかなー？
but I wonder if anyone was able to find their own?
見つけたら、いっぱい写真撮っといてくださいねー！
If you found it, make sure to take lots of screenshots, okay?
はーい！
Yay!
というわけで3曲をお届けしたんですけど、
So I just delivered those three songs to you,
かっこいいもあり、かわいいもあり、いかがでしたか？
with cool vibes and cute vibes! How did you like it?
え、そう！ ステージ、流れ星
Oh, right! On stage, shooting stars
バーンって降ってきたの！
came raining down with a bam!
ほら見て！ 星空ー！
Look at that! A starry sky!
すごい、このステージね、マジ無限の可能性を感じるんだよね。
Amazing! I really feel endless possibilities on this stage.
何でもできる気がする！ うん。
I feel like I can do anything! Yeah.
いや、ホロメンと一緒に歌えるの楽しいなー。
Man, it's so much fun being able to sing with my Hololive friends.
1年に1回のこのライブ、思い切り好きなことできるのがすごい楽しい。
In this once-a-year live, getting to do whatever I love to my heart's content is so fun!
そして衣装も久しぶりに、和装でございます！
And for my outfit, for the first time in a while, it's traditional Japanese attire!
あにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ！
A-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya!
そう、『ワールドイズマイン』はね、ちょっとかぐやのやつでいいなって思って、歌いたくなっちゃったので、
Yeah, for "World Is Mine", I loved Kaguya-sama's version and really wanted to sing it,
せっかくだから、かぐやに合わせて和装でね、歌ってみましたー！
so since I had the chance, I matched Kaguya and tried singing it in Japanese attire!
「欠点？ かわいいの間違いでしょ！」
"Flaws? You must mean cute quirks, right!"
ポンだっていいでしょ！
Being a bit clumsy is fine too, right?
まあ今日ポンはしてないんですけどもねー。
Well, I haven't been clumsy today, though!
なぜか知らないけど、歌だけは高性能って言われるしなー。
For some reason, people always say only my singing is high-spec!
はーい！
Yep!
でも、今そんな「空ー！」って言ってたけど…
But anyway, I was just shouting "The sky!" like that, but...
今日限りでまた海に沈んじゃうんだって、この場所
They say this place will sink back into the ocean after today.
そんなのもったいないよねー
That's such a waste, isn't it?
ロボサーなんかいい方法知らない？
Robosa, do you know any good ideas?
ボクが高性能だからきっと知ってるかなーと思って
I thought since I'm high-spec, maybe you'd know...
うん。ふんふん、ふんふん。
Hmm. Mhm, mhm.
あっ、ひらめいた！
Ah, I've got an idea!
海は海でも、電子の海に沈めちゃえばいいんだー！
If it's the sea, we can just sink it into the digital sea!
い、いいんだー！
Y-Yeah, that works!
そうだよなー！
That's right!
というわけで、ちょっとやっちゃおうかなー
So, I guess I'll go ahead and do it!
お願いしまーす！
Here goes!
パチン
Snap!
これパチンってなった？
Did that snap properly?
悲しみの海に沈んだ私 目を開けるのも億劫
Sunk into a sea of sadness, it's a chore to even open my eyes.
このままどこまでも堕ちて行き 誰にも見つけられないのかな
Falling endlessly like this, will no one ever find me?
どこへ向かい 何をすれば？
Where should I head? What should I do?
ふと射し込む一筋の光
Suddenly, a single ray of light shines through.
手を伸ばせば届きそうだけど
If I reach out, it seems I could touch it,
波に攫われて見失った
but swept away by the waves, I lost sight of it.
あれは一体なんだったのかな
Just what in the world was that?
あたたかくて眩しかったの
It was so warm and dazzling.
無意識のカウンターイルミネーション
An unconscious counter-illumination...
嘘つきは誰？
Who is the liar?
深海少女 まだまだ沈む
Deep sea girl, sinking further and further,
暗闇の彼方へ閉じこもる
shutting herself away beyond the darkness.
深海少女 だけど知りたい
Deep sea girl, but she wants to know,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
because she found the one who captivated her heart.
昼も夜も無かったこの場所
In this place where neither day nor night existed,
なのに眠れない夜は続く
sleepless nights continue nonetheless.
自由の羽大きく広げて
Spreading your wings of freedom wide,
泳ぐあなたは綺麗でした
swimming, you were so beautiful.
そしてまた光は降り注ぐ
And then, light pours down once more.
見とれていたら目が合った
As I watched entranced, our eyes met.
気付いてこっちを振り返るあなたに
To you, who noticed and looked back at me,
嘘つきな私
I am a liar...
深海少女 わざわざ沈む
Deep sea girl, sinking on purpose,
暗闇のさなかに赤い頬
cheeks blushing red in the midst of darkness.
深海少女 ハダカの心を見せる勇気
Deep sea girl, the courage to bare her naked heart...
黒い海がまだ許さない
The black sea still won't allow it.
こんなに服は汚れてしまった
My clothes have gotten so dirty.
笑顔も醜くゆがんでいった
Even my smile became distorted and ugly.
誰にも合わせる顔なんてないの
I have no face I could show to anyone!
もう放っておいてよ！
Just leave me alone!
声にならない気持ちが溢れてとけた
Feelings I couldn't put into words overflowed and dissolved.
次の瞬間 君が突然姿を消した
The next moment, you suddenly disappeared.
心配性の 彼女は焦る
Worry-prone as she is, she panics.
闇が彼を隠しひとりきり
The darkness hides him, leaving him all alone.
限界少女 その手を伸ばす
Girl at her limit, reaching out her hand.
「ほらね、君も素敵な色を隠してた」
"See? You were hiding lovely colors too."
深海少女 腕を引かれる
Deep sea girl, pulled by the arm,
歌う祝福のマリンスノー
singing a blessing of marine snow.
深海少女 もっと知りたい
Deep sea girl, she wants to know more,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
because she found the one who captivated her heart.
この海を出て
Leaving this sea,
今飛び立つの
now I will take flight!
常識化生理感モテモテ
Making sense of bodily feelings, oh so popular,
経済的余裕もモテモテ
financial comfort too, oh so popular,
クラウンは埋めた 指輪もあげた
I buried the crown, gave the ring away...
印鑑押したら とうとう負けだね
Once we stamp the seal, we've finally lost, haven't we?
愛だの恋だのそんなもんは感情論でしょ
Love and romance, that sort of thing is just emotionalism, right?
でも婚前交渉する時めっちゃいいでしょ
But premarital intimacy feels so good, doesn't it?
震える心 疼いてる身体
A trembling heart, an aching body,
裏腹 くわばら (逃げてー！)
Contradictory, heaven forbid! (Run away!)
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
あなたの顔しか拝めない
I can only look upon your face.
病める時も 健やかな時も
In sickness and in health,
手を取り合うのが運命
Holding each other's hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
ようやく一つになれるかな
Can we finally become one?
いつかあなた 香り変わって
Someday, your scent will change,
シワだらけになって
You'll be covered in wrinkles,
触れる肌も背中合わせ
Even touching skin, we'll turn back-to-back,
憧れが腐って
And our yearning will rot away.
本当に大事なモノをあげた人でも
Even to the person you gave what matters most,
期待が普通に呑まれるのね
Expectations are swallowed up as ordinary, huh?
純情ばっか並べて嫌になっちゃうでしょ
Listing only pure feelings makes you sick of it, right?
どうせ裏切り合うのが見えるでしょ
You can see we'll just betray each other anyway, right?
壊れる未来があるならば
If there is only a broken future ahead,
お伽話なんか (やめてー！)
Then fairy tales and the like—(Stop it!)
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
あなたの顔しか拝めない
I can only look upon your face.
病める時も 健やかな時も
In sickness and in health,
手を取り合うのが運命
Holding each other's hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
ようやく一つになれるかな
Can we finally become one?
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
Let's get married, let's do just that,
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
あなたの顔しか拝めない
I can only look upon your face.
病める時も 健やかな時も
In sickness and in health,
手を取り合うのが運命
Holding each other's hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that,
ようやく一つになれるかな
Can we finally become one?
ああ...
Ah...
ねえ ニア
Hey, Near,
誰かを笑い飛ばさなきゃ
Unless I laugh someone off,
自分を許せないような
I can't even forgive myself—
くだらない人間のこと
About foolish humans like that,
君はどう思う？
What do you think?
ねえ ニア
Hey, Near,
他人の歩幅を眺めて
Watching other people's stride,
意味もなく駆け足になる
And breaking into a run without reason—
つまらない人間のこと
About boring humans like that,
君はどう思う？
What do you think?
ねえ ニア
Hey, Near...
ハロー ハロー アイム ニア フー アー ユー？
Hello, hello, I'm Near, who are you?
ハロー ハロー アイム ニア
Hello, hello, I'm Near...
ねえ ニア
Hey, Near,
笑顔で過ごす日々を
The days spent smiling,
当たり前と思うような
As if taking them for granted—
盲目な人間のこと
About blind humans like that,
君はどう思う？
What do you think?
形のない不確かなものはいつだって
Things without shape and uncertain always
計算を狂わせてしまうの
End up throwing off calculations.
だけど...
And yet...
ああ 僕はまだ信じてる
Ah, I still believe.
心のない君に問いかけたのは
The reason I asked a heartless you
君の手が 僕よりも温かかったからさ
Was because your hand was warmer than mine.
ハロー ハロー アイム ニア フー アー ユー？
Hello, hello, I'm Near, who are you?
ハロー ハロー アイム ニア
Hello, hello, I'm Near...
ねえ ニア
Hey, Near,
子供の頃に見てた あの夢の続きが
The continuation of that dream I had as a child
こんな未来...
Is a future like this...
いつ願ってたこと
What do you think about...
君はどう思う
...the things I once wished for?
I am always by your side, Near
ああ 僕らはまた勘違い
Ah, we misunderstood once again.
明日のない暗いこの空の下
Beneath this dark sky with no tomorrow,
君の手が僕よりも震えていた気がした
I felt like your hand was trembling more than mine.
Hello, Hello, I'm Near, who are you?
Hello, Hello, I'm Near
ねえニア
Hey, Near,
誰かを笑い飛ばさなきゃ
unless we laugh someone off,
自分を許せないような
we can't seem to forgive ourselves.
くだらない僕たちのこと
About how pathetic we are,
君はどう思う
what do you think?
ああ 僕はまた期待してる
Ah, I'm having hopes once again.
ボロボロでも見る影もないけれど
Even if I'm battered and a shadow of my former self,
君がいるこの星を忘れたくはないんだよ
I don't want to forget this planet where you are.
ああ 僕はまた信じてる
Ah, I'm believing once again.
眠らない君に問いかけたのは
The reason I asked you, who never sleeps,
君の手が僕よりも温かかったからさ
is because your hand was warmer than mine.
温かかったからさ
Because it was warmer.
Hello, Hello, I'm Near, I love you
垂れ流したテレビの音
The sound of the TV left playing,
溜めてしまった洗濯物は今日こそ
the laundry that's piled up—today, for sure,
晴れててもあえて外には出ないでいよう
even if it's sunny, let's purposely not go outside.
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's make a toast with unphotogenic snacks and alcohol.
2人酸いも甘いも噛み合わないとしても
Even if the two of us don't see eye to eye on the sweet and sour,
お互い寄り添うように少しずらしてみようよ
let's shift a little so we can snuggle close.
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないよう
So the sun you gave me won't be hidden by the moon,
輝きやまぬように歌うメロディー
a melody sung so its sparkle never fades.
戯れる slowly flowing day
Frolicking on a slowly flowing day,
愛してるも通り越して
even moving past "I love you,"
似た者同士こうして
two kindred spirits like this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want us to laugh together until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you with a morning call,
I'll protect you from nightmares, baby
脱ぎっぱなしの足跡辿ると
Following the trail of discarded clothes,
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
you catch me off guard and hug me from behind.
つい、繰り返すと忘れてしまいそうになるよ
If we repeat it, I almost casually forget...
振り返ると日々が当たり前じゃないこと
...that looking back, these daily moments aren't guaranteed.
2人対の細胞
The two of us, a pair of cells,
絡み合う特別を
intertwining our special bond,
噛み締めて生きたいと思った微睡む抱く正午
I want to live savoring it, embracing a midday slumber.
吐息、漏れた体温
A sigh, leaking warmth,
微塵も逃さないよう
so not a single speck slips away,
頭の中刻む甘いメモリー
a sweet memory etched inside my mind.
戯れる slowly flowing day
Frolicking on a slowly flowing day,
愛してるも通り越して
even moving past "I love you,"
違う者同士こうして
two different souls like this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want us to laugh together until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you with a morning call,
I'll protect you from nightmares, baby
重ねた手はね...
Our joined hands, you see...
離さないでいて
Don't let go of me,
ごめん、これ そばに居たいだけだね
I'm sorry, I just want to be by your side.
抱えた想いはお互い様でしょう
The feelings we hold are mutual, right?
ほら おあいこでしょう
See, we're even.
すれ違い 間違いもあるし
We have our misunderstandings and mistakes,
筋書き通りいかない打診
and things that don't go according to plan,
悲しみだって半分こにしよう
but let's share the sorrow fifty-fifty.
別れじゃない希望 独りよがりにならないように いつも
It's hope, not goodbye—so we never become self-centered, always...
Oh...
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで
Without you, even now, somewhere...
動けないままの僕で
I'd remain unable to move,
ありがとう伝えたいのです
so I want to tell you \"thank you.\"
これからは僕が支えてくって
Saying that from now on, I'll support you,
呆れてしまうくらいにね
to the point where you're left amazed,
愛が増していくday by day
love keeps growing day by day.
面と向かうとなんだか
When facing you directly, somehow,
素直になれないな ごめんね
I can't be honest with myself, I'm sorry.
戯れるSlowly flowing day
Playfully spending a slowly flowing day,
愛してるも通り越して
going way beyond \"I love you,\"
似た者同士こうして
two birds of a feather like this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to keep laughing until we grow old.
君がいなきゃlonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed within a dream,
起こすからmorning callで
I'll wake you up with a morning call,
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
はーい！というわけで、
Alright! So,
今回は『深海少女』と、
this time, we had \"Shinkai Shoujo,\"
すーと一緒に歌った『未完成』、
\"Mikansei,\" which I sang with Su-chan,
『今宵もう』、そして、
\"Koyoi Mou,\" and then,
『ニア』、『W/X/Y』でしたー！
\"Near,\" and \"W/X/Y\"!
初出しの曲も何個かあって、いかがでしたかー？
There were several songs performed for the first time, how did you like it?
えっ、すーとのやつ可愛かったでしょう？
Eh, the one with Su-chan was so cute, wasn't it?
そう、いっぱい曲のあったんだけど、
Yeah, there were so many songs,
うーん、これ！ってなったやつがこちらでございました。
but the ones where I went, \"Mhm, this is it!\" were these.
これにはまたね、裏話があると思いますので、
There are behind-the-scenes stories about this,
またおしゃべりしたいなーと思います。
so I'd love to chat about it again!
ねえ、みんなのイラストもね、降ってまいりましたー！
Hey, everyone's illustrations came raining down too!
可愛かったでしょう。
They were so cute, right?
そして！
And then!
僕のパッチンで深海に降りてきたんだけど、
We descended into the deep sea with my finger snap,
やばくにゃい？
but isn't that insane?
僕、パッチンの才能あったかもしんない。
I might actually have a talent for finger snapping.
音は聞こえなかったんだけどさ、
Even though you couldn't hear the sound,
うーん、いけるらしい。
mhm, apparently it works!
そして！ブランシュドール衣装でございます！
And! This is the Blanche Doll outfit!
実はこの衣装、ライブの3Dで着るのは初めてー！
Actually, this is the very first time I'm wearing this outfit in a 3D live!
表情もちゃんと変わります。可愛いでしょ？
The facial expressions change properly too. Isn't it cute?
ふん！
Hm!
ねえ、可愛いでしょ。
Right, it's cute, isn't it?
今回はこちらの衣装をもとに、アトロポリスは作られておりますー！
This time, Atropolis was built based on this outfit!
かわいい、かわいい、ふわふわ、あ！
So cute, so cute, so fluffy... ah!
これ、あ！待って、これK-POPの、あ、このカメラ！
This, ah! Wait, this is the K-POP... ah, this camera!
あ、速い！待って！
Ah, it's fast! Wait!
ちょっと、K-POPのアイドルで、見たことあるカメラだ！
Wait, it's that camera I've seen with K-POP idols!
カメラの場所探すのこれ？
Do I have to search for where the camera is?
え、待って、今のも見つけらん深刻だった！
Eh, wait, I couldn't find the last one either!
ここ！
Here!
ここ！ここ！ここー！
Here! Here! Here!
あ、え？どこ？
Ah, eh? Where?
やばい！
Oh no!
やばい、え、どここれ？
Oh no, eh, where is it?
手挙げたら余計分かんないんだけど！
Raising my hand makes it even harder to tell!
ここー！
Here!
ここ、え？
Here, eh?
ここ！
Here!
うわ、違う！
Whoa, wrong one!
ここ！ここ！ここー！
Here! Here! Here!
え、合ってる？ここ？
Eh, is that right? Here?
え、ここじゃない？
Eh, not here?
こっ、違うのなんか？
Th-this isn't it?
あれれれ？
Huh? Wait, wait...
え？
Eh?
次！
Next!
えー？
Ehh?
ここー！
Here!
分かるんだよねー。
I've got this down.
ここー！
Here!
あー！
Ahhh!
という... やばい、びっくりした。
And so... Man, that caught me off guard.
なんか既視感を感じた。
I felt some serious déjà vu.
結構カメラ難しいのかもしれない。
Finding the camera might actually be pretty tricky.
楽しかった！
That was fun!
というわけで、なんとここで重大告知がありまーす！
And so, we actually have a major announcement right now!
それではこちらの動画をご覧ください。
Now then, please take a look at this video.
どうぞ！
Here it is!
ロボ子さん 1st Album
[Roboco-san 1st Album]
発売決定
[Release Confirmed]
ろぼさーのみんな、お待たせー！
To all the Robosa, thank you for waiting!
ついに、ロボ子の1stアルバム『Jewel Memory』の発売が決定したよー！
The release of Roboco's 1st album, "Jewel Memory," has finally been decided!
これまでろぼさーと一緒に過ごしてきた時間や思い出のひとつひとつが、
Every single moment and memory I've spent together with Robosa so far...
ロボ子にとっては宝物、宝石なんだ！
...is a treasure, a jewel to me!
だから、その宝石を収めた宝箱のようなアルバムになってほしいなっていう思いを込めたよ。
So I poured my heart into making it an album like a treasure chest to hold all those gems.
収録楽曲の順番や構成にもこだわっているから、楽しみにしててね！
I put a lot of care into the track order and composition too, so please look forward to it!
なんと新曲も収録されるよー！
What's more, brand-new songs will be included!
さらに同梱物には、アルバム本体を飾って保管できる特製アクリルケースが付いてくるんだ！
Furthermore, the package includes a special acrylic case where you can display and store the album!
ロボ子の他のグッズと一緒にお部屋に飾ってね！
Please display it in your room along with Roboco's other merch!
他にもみんなが喜んでくれるような同梱物を用意しているよ！
We've prepared other included goodies that everyone will love too!
詳細は予約ページを見てね！
Check out the pre-order page for details!
CD予約の開始はこの後21時から！
CD pre-orders start tonight from 21:00!
ろぼさーはちゃんとチェックするんだよー！
Robosa, be sure to check it out!
はーい！ということでなんと、アルバムが出まーす！
All right! So believe it or not, I'm releasing an album!
詳しくは、販売サイト等を確認してみてください！
For details, please check the sales site and more!
えー、お待たせしました！
Um, thank you for waiting!
やっとアルバム出せたー！嬉しい！
I was finally able to release an album! I'm so happy!
え、めちゃめちゃかっこよくなかったですか？ビジュ！
Um, wasn't the visual super cool?
一体何が入っているのか、全部で10曲あるんですけれども、
As for what's inside, there are 10 tracks in total, but...
3曲、なんと新しい新曲ありますよー！
...amazingly, 3 of them are brand-new songs!
楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to it!
そして、この後はなんと、そのアルバムの中から1曲の新曲、披露したいなと思います！
And after this, believe it or not, I'd like to perform one of the new songs from the album!
さらにこの配信の後、MV... MV... M... MV？ん？MV... ん？分かんなくなってきたわ。
Furthermore, after this stream, the MV... MV... M... MV? Huh? MV... Huh? I lost track.
MVもプレミア公開されるので、ぜひみんなチェックしてってください！
The MV will also have a premiere, so please be sure to check it out, everyone!
あ、ちなみに僕の歌声にメロメロになった方は、今すぐメンバーに入って、
Ah, by the way, if you fell head over heels for my singing voice, join the membership right now...
この後、メン限の配信もありまーすよー！
...because there'll be a member-exclusive stream after this too!
1曲歌いますよー！
I'll sing a song there too!
もうちょっとね、ろぼさーと楽しみたいと思います。
I want to enjoy a little more time with Robosa.
まだこれで終わりじゃないんだから！
Because this isn't the end just yet!
この配信が終わってもプレミア動画もあるし、メンバー限定配信もあるので、ぜひ両方とも楽しみにしててください！
Even after this stream ends, there's the premiere video and member-only stream, so please look forward to both!
新曲は、みんな漢字の名前を間違えないようにしてね。
For the new song, make sure everyone gets the kanji name right.
『現世アリス』。
"Utsusemi Alice."
ちょっとメロい...かも？
It might be a bit mellow... maybe?
それでは、最後の曲、聴いてってください！
Now then, please listen to the final song!
『現世アリス』。
"Utsusemi Alice."
不思議の国や御伽噺でも
Even beyond wonderlands or fairy tales,
見れない現実までご招待
you're invited to a reality never seen before.
現世アリス
[Song: Utsusemi Alice]
異国に取り残されたみたいだ
Like being left behind in a foreign land,
知らない言葉に戸惑う
baffled by unfamiliar words.
誰もが心を嘘で隠して
Everyone hides their heart behind lies,
本音を作ろった　どれが正体？
patching over true feelings—which is the real them?
今くらいは曝け出してよ
At least for now, lay it all bare.
君の後悔　吐き出してみて
Try spitting out your regrets.
画面越しの悲しいニュースに酔って
Drunk on sad news through the screen,
ふと仲間の些細なミスに怒って
suddenly angry over a companion's trivial mistake,
囚われて流されて　日々に嫌気さしても
trapped and swept along, even if you grow sick of each day...
忘れられぬような光景を
An unforgettable sight...
君に届けるから
...I'll bring to you,
その目に焼き付けてみて
so try burning it into your eyes.
ねぇ
Hey...
忘れさせるなんて大層なことは言えないけど
I can't make grand claims like making you forget it all, but...
ちょっとでも寄り添えるように
...so that I can stay by your side even a little,
夜明けまで連れ出すよ
I'll take you away until dawn.
コンクリートの森を彷徨えば
If I wander through this concrete jungle,
見慣れた街だって迷路
even this familiar town becomes a maze.
誰もが自分をお役で演じて
Everyone acts out their assigned role,
笑顔が貼り付いた これが正体
with smiles plastered on—that's the reality.
無理に笑わなくていい
You don't have to force a smile,
仮面なんて剥がして
just tear off that mask.
窓に映る 君を抱いて
Embracing the you reflected in the window.
流行り物の空虚なダンスに舞って
Dancing to the empty rhythm of passing trends,
また不機嫌な他人の声に怯えて
frightened once again by the irritable voices of others.
疑って 躓いて 明日におびえても
Even if you doubt, stumble, and fear tomorrow,
消えやしないような感情を
these emotions that will never fade away,
君と分け合うから
I will share them with you,
その声を聞かせてみて ねえ
so let me hear your voice, hey...
救い出すだなんて傲慢なことは言えないけど
I can't say something as arrogant as "I'll save you,"
ちょっとでも軽くなるように
but just to make your burden a little lighter,
その手を引くよ アリス
I'll take your hand, Alice.